Peter Sharp

PHYSICS TUTOR · EDUCATIONAL CONSULTANT

The Gables, High Street, Fovant, Wiltshire. SP3 5JL

■ 07764 677295 | ■ peter@petersharp.education | In mrpsharp



Summary_

I am an experienced school leader who works with schools supporting them through quality assurance and teacher training. I also offer Physics tutoring for A-Level students applying to the most competitive universities.

Current Roles_____

Peter Sharp Education

Sept 2021 -

DIRECTOR

• Working with schools and individuals to improve outcomes. I deliver INSET, review compliance and assess eduactional quality to help schools prepare for inspection. I also work with students to help them prepare for university.

Christ's School, Richmond

Nov 2017 -

CHAIR OF GOVERNORS

• Chair of the governing body from September 2022

Cambridge Assessment, OCR

June 2022 -

ASSISTANT EXAMINER

· Assistant Examiner for OCR Physics A, Internation A-Level Physics and SEAB A-Level Physics

Previous Experience_____

Westminster School

Sept. 2008 - Sept. 2021

DEPUTY HEAD (ACADEMIC)

Sept. 2019 - Sept. 2021

- · Overseeing all aspects of the academic programme from admissions to final university placements.
- Member of senior team overseeing the running of the school throughout the challenge of the pandemic.

DIRECTOR OF TEACHING AND LEARNING

Jan. 2018 – Sept. 2019

• Overseeing the quality of education provided including a particular focus on EdTech, supporting SEND students and quality of assessment. Also in charge of staffing links with Harris Westminster Sixth Form.

TEACHER OF PHYSICS Sept. 2008 – Sept. 2021

• Teaching students in Years 9-13 Physics including IGCSE, A-Level and Pre-U.

Independent Schools' Inspectorate

Sept. 2018 - Jan. 2022

TEAM INSPECTOR, COMPLIANCE TEAM INSPECTOR

Highgate School Sept. 2005 – Sept. 2008

TEACHER OF PHYSICS

• Teaching GCSE and A-Level Physics to Year 9-13, plus Science to Years 7 and 8.

The Scientific Alliance Nov. 2003 – Sept. 2004

RESEARCH OFFICER

Education

Birkbeck, University of London

Sept. 2011 - Sept. 2013

BA PHILOSOPHY, YEARS 1 & 2

Years 1 & 2 of a part-time degree in Philosophy. I discontinued these studies due to a relocation but continue to read Philosophy informally.

Institute of Education, London

Sept. 2004 - Sept. 2005

PGCE SECONDARY SCIENCE

Imperial College, London

Sept. 2002 - Sept. 2003

MSc. Environmental Technology

University of Cambridge

Sept. 1999 - Sept. 2002

MA NATURAL SCIENCES

The King's School, Canterbury

Sept. 1994 - Aug. 1999

- A-Levels: Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Geology (all A)
- AS-Level: Further Mathematics (A)
- STEP Physics: 1

Wider Interests_

SPORT AND THE OUTDOORS

I am passionate about the outdoors and have spent much of my career taking students on walking, climbing and rowing trips.

- Qualified Mountain Leader (ML)
- · Minibus D1 licence
- · Experienced rowing coach
- RYA Powerboat Level 2

ENVIRONMENTAL TECHNOLOGY

I am committed to low-impact living and I am currently living off-grid in a narrowboat on the canals. I am experimenting with different technologies in an attempt to live a full 21st-century life-style with minimal impact on the planet.

References

Mr. Patrick Derham

Mrs. Sam Burnett

Ex-Headmaster, Westminster School

Vice-chair of Governing Body and ex-clerk Christ's School

4 Quarry Lane Charlbury Oxon OX7 3RN

Queen's Road Richmond TW10 6HW

patricksjderham@gmail.com

sburnett@christs.school

07775 725523

07979 750452